Guide to the Brian McGinn Papers AIA.015
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI: Leeward Islands/Montserrat, 1642-2002; 2.13 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 7 folders in a second record carton, 21 folders in a third record carton, and 1 folder in a legal sized manuscript box.
  - Montserrat: Emerald Community Singers/Montserrat Dance, 1992-1999 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Montserrat: Facts, 1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Montserrat: Farrell/O'Farrill Family of Montserrat, 1769-1997 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Montserrat: French Family, 1894, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Montserrat: Forts, 1729 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Montserrat: Galway Pedigree, 1871-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Montserrat: General Articles/Information, 1924-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Montserrat: Governors 17th Century, 1915-1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Montserrat: Hay of Haystown/Earl of Carlisle Patents, 1926-1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Montserrat: Hay Manuscripts and Transcriptions, 1642-1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Montserrat: "If Irish Ran the World: Montserrat 1630-1730" (book review), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Montserrat: Irish Influence - Articles I, 1954-2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Montserrat: Irish Influence - Articles II, 1954-2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Montserrat: Irish Language 1913-1937, 2000, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Montserrat: Language/Brogue, 1905-2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Montserrat: The Laws of Montserrat and Census 1729-1730 (photocopies of originals), undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Montserrat: Life and Correspondence of Ldoowick Bryskett, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Montserrat: Lynch Pedigree, 1894, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Montserrat: Memories of Montserrat: History, Myths and More (booklet), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Montserrat: Messenger, John - Articles, 1966-1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Montserrat: Pedigrees, Various, 1894-1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Montserrat: Photographs (of McGinn), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Montserrat: Pictures/Maps (includes slides of images in publications), 1972, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Montserrat: Power Family, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Montserrat: Pulsipher, Lydia Hilelic - Articles, 1982-1994 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Montserrat: Religion I, 1886-1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Montserrat: Religion II, 1886-1997 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Montserrat: Slavery, 1972, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Montserrat: St. Patrick's Day, 1827-1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Montserrat: Stapleton Pedigree, 1922-1995 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Montserrat: Virginia, 1642-1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Montserrat: Volcano Geological History I, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Montserrat: Volcano Geological History II, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Montserrat: Unidentified Source "CSP" I, 1600s (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Montserrat: Unidentified Source "CSP" II, 1600s (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Series VII: West Indies, 1665-2002; 3.2 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 14 folders in a third record carton, 4 folders in a fourth record carton, and 14 folders in a legal sized manuscript box.
  This series contains research materials about the Irish Diaspora in the West Indies. The contents of this series include photocopies of articles and sometimes books, as well as bibliographic information used by McGinn for his research.
  - Antigua and Barbuda I, 1849-2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Antigua and Barbuda II, 1849-2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Antigua: Bridgetown, 1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Antigua: Census, 1849 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Antigua: Famine 1847 Donation, 1847-1997 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Antigua: Merchants, 1971-1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Antigua: Jamaica, Montserrat - Brown, 1756-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Atlantic Island, 1962, 1982-1984, 1992, 1998-2000 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Bahamas 18th Century, 1962-1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Barbados, 1905-1987 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Barbados: Bibliography, 1965-1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Barbados: Irish I, 1874-2001 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Barbados: Irish II, 1874-2001 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Barbados: Irish III, 1874-2001 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Barbados: Red Legs, 1962-2001 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Caribbean: Irish, 1939-1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Caribbean: Irish Migration, 1954-1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Colonists in Bondage" - Smith, Abbott Emerson, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Cromwell I, 1865-2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Cromwell II, 1865-2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cuba, Puerto Rico and Spanish Louisiana I, 1960-2002 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Cuba, Puerto Rico and Spanish Louisiana II, 1960-2002 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Dominica: Bellews, 1936-1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Dutch in the Caribbean, 1903-1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - English in the Caribbean: Bridenbaugh, Earl and Roberta, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - French West Indies: Haiti, Martinque I, 1940-1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - French West Indies: Haiti, Martinque II, 1940-1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Galway Merchants: Wine, Provision Trade I, 1922-1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Galway Merchants: Wine, Provision Trade II, 1922-1996 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Grenada: Catholic Church - O'Hannan, Fr. Anthony, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Gwynn, Aubrey: Research Notes - West Indies, 1665-1931 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Gwynn Documents Relating to Irish, 1932, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Jamaica: 17th Century, 1989-1999 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Jamaica: Black Irish, 1932-1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Jamaica: Irish I, 1848-2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jamaica: Irish II, 1848-2002 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Jamaica: Maroons, 1989-1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Jesuit: West Indies South America, 1949, 1976, 1986, 1995-1996 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Migration and the Origins of the English Atlantic World (Alison Gomes), 1999 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Pirates S. American Caribbean, 1961-1968, 1976, 1987, 1995-1998 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
  - Puerto Rico: Irish, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Redonda: Irish (see also Leeward Islands), 1984-1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - St. Croix-Danish West Indies: Tuite Family, 1917-1999 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - St. Kitts/Nevis, 1855-1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - St. Kitts: Census, 1678 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Tortuga: Irish, 1966-1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Trinidad and Tobago, 1894-1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Turks and Caicos, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - West Indies: Craton and Fryer articles, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - West Indies: Gwynn Articles, 1929-1948 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - West Indies: Indentured Servants (versus Slavery) I, 1911-2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - West Indies: Indentured Servants (versus Slavery) II, 1911-2001 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - West Indies: Irish Provisional Trade, 1921-1998 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - West Indies: Irish Provisional Trade, 1937-1992 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - West Indies: Merchants and Planters (18th Century), 1931-1988 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - West Indies: Merchants and Planters (18th Century), 1960-1993 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - West Indies: Unidentified Source "CSP" (18th Century), 1711-1717 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Series VIII: Latin America, 1817-2004; 4.16 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 11 folders in a third record carton, 3 folders in a legal sized manuscript box, 4 folders in an additional legal sized manuscript box, and 1 folder in a shared oversized flat box.
  This series contains research materials about the Irish Diaspora in Latin America. The contents of this series include photocopies of articles and sometimes books, as well as bibliographic information used by McGinn for his research.
  - Argentina: Brown, Guillermo Admiral, 1925-1940 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Argentina: Brown, Guillermo Admiral (Argentine Naval Founder), 1943-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Argentina: Brown, Guillermo Admiral, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Argentina: Brown, Guillermo Admiral, 1963-1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Argentina: Brown, Guillermo: Admiral Brown Project/Foxford Woolen Mills I, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Argentina: Brown, Guillermo: Admiral Brown Project/Foxford Woolen Mills II, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Argentina: Buenos Aires: British Invasions; Irish Soldiers, 1962-1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Argentina: Bulfin, William, 1948-2001, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Argentina: Cattle Brands, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Argentina: Chile - Wars of Independence, 1980-1997 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Argentina: Coughlan, Eduardo, 1982-1987 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Argentina: Hurling, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Argentina: English-speaking Communities - Andrew Graham-Yooll article, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Argentina: Guevera Lynch I (Che Guevera ancestry), 1939-1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Argentina: Guevera Lynch I (Che Guevera ancestry), 1939-1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Argentina: Irish Argentine Society - St. Patrick's Day Parade Images, 1990-1991, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Argentina: Mulhall Family (press), 1869-1908, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Argentina: Irish Immigrants I, 1863, 1931-1997 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Argentina: Irish Immigrants II, 1863, 1931-1997 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Argentina: MacLoughlin, Guillermo, 1994-1998 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Argentina: Malvinas Island (Falkland Islands), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Argentina: Maps, Facts, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Argentina: Magazine Articles, 1993, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Argentina: Modern Day, 1995, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Argentina: Murray, Thomas - "The Story of the Irish in Argentina I (pp. 1-259), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Argentina: Murray, Thomas - "The Story of the Irish in Argentina II (pp. 260-514), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Argentina: O'Rielly, Diego, 1910-1995 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Argentina: Southern Cross - Centennial Edition 1875-1975 (serial) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Argentina: Spanish American War articles, 1937, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Argentina: The Standard, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Argentina: Thesis "19th Century Irish Emigration to and Settlement in Argentina" by Patrick McKenna I (pp. 1-165), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Argentina: Thesis "19th Century Irish Emigration to and Settlement in Argentina" by Patrick McKenna II (pp. 166-299), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Argentina: Thesis "19th Century Irish Emigration to and Settlement in Argentina" by Patrick McKenna III (pp. 300-end), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Biblio: Irish/Lat Am, 1999-2004 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Brazil 1612-1640, 1878-1991 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Brazil 1612-1640, 1927-1991 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Brazil: 19th and 20th Century, 1848-2001 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Brazil: 19th and 20th Century, 1968-1995 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Brazil: Amazon Irish - Gwynn, Aubrey, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Brazil: Casement, Roger, 1969-1993 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Brazil: Cotter Expedition, 1817-1998 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Brazil: List of Illustrations - Amazon, 1980-1991, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Brazil: Macauley, Neill, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Brazil: MacDonnell, Martin / O'Brien Chronicle, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Brazil: McGinn Photographs (prints), undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Brazil: Taperoa, 1893-1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Central America, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Chile, 1851-2000 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Ecuador: 1964-1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Ecuador: Sades, Arthur, 1899-2004 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - English Language Press in Latin America, 1983-2000 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Fr. Michael Wadding S.J., 1921, 1930, 1954, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Ferguson, William O., 1826-1997 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Irish in Latin America, 1893-1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Irish Legion: Brown, Hugo Blair Dr., 1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Irish Legion: Correspondence - O'Connell, Daniel, 1973-1991 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Irish Legion: Maps and Pictures (includes copies of images used in publication), 1929-1991 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Irish Legion: Research I, 1827-2002 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Irish Legion: Research II, 1827-2002 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Irish Life 17th Century: Old English Language, 1966-1994 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Irish Soldiers in South America, 1963-1987 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - The Irish in South America, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 065, Folder 8)
  - Irish in South America Bibliography, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Lambert, Eric: Voluntarios Britanicos Tomo 1 I, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Lambert, Eric: Voluntarios Britanicos Tomo 1 II, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Lambert, Eric: Bolivar's Legionnaires, Correspondence regarding, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lema, Gonzalo, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lynch Family of Argentina, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1987-1995 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Catholic Reporter, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - O'Connor, F.B., 1836-2004 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - O'Gormans Juan and Edmundo, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - O'Leary, D.G., 1937-2001 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Paraguay, 1963-1999 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Peru, 1972-1997 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Quincentennial: Spanish Settlement - Hispanic Legacy, 1991-1996 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Refugio and San Patrocio Colonies, 1999-2004 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - South America, 1992-2005 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Uruguay: Banda Oriental, 1836-1998 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Venezuela, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Series IX: Europe and Asia, Africa, et. al., 1825-2002; 2.71 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 12 folders in a second record carton, 1 legal sized manuscript box, 12 folders in a second legal sized manuscript box, and 7 folders in a third legal sized manuscript box.
  This series contains research materials about the Irish Diaspora in Europe, Asia, Mexico, Africa, et al. The contents of this series include photocopies of articles and sometimes books, as well as bibliographic information used by McGinn for his research.
  - Irish Abroad: General I, 1986-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Irish Abroad: General II, 1986-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Diaspora: General; President Mary Robinson (Irl) piece, 1976-1998 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Australia, 1992-1997 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Austria I, 1892, 1951-2002 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Austria II, 1892, 1951-2002 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Bishop Thomas Quinlan, 1970-1973 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "By the Help of Many Lies or How Penal were the Penal Laws?" (MacCarthy Mur), 1990 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Britain, 1998, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - British Army I, 1909, 1957-2001 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - British Army II, 1909, 1957-2001 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Casement, Roger: 1916 POW Brigade, 1969-1998, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "Catholic Social Classes Under the Penal Laws" (Louis M. Cullen), 1990 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Columbus Voyages I, 1925-1998 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Columbus Voyages II, 1825-1998 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - "Converts" (Thomas P. Power), 1990 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - County Monaghan Map, undated (Flat-file-folder 6, Flat-file-folder 1)
  - "Diaspora and Comparison: The Global Irish as a Case Study" (Kevin Kenny), 2003 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - "Did Ireland Ever Have a Black Community?" (Anthony Breen), 2002 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Encyclopedia of Ireland (Gill and Macmillan), undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Encyclopedia of Irish America (NDP), 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Famine Diary, 1970-1995 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Flanders, 1947-1964 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - France I, 1917, 1939-2000, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - France II, 1917, 1939-2000, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Galway Roots - Clanna na Gaillimhe (Journal of the Galway Family Historical Society), 1994-1995 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - A Guide to Irish Bibliographical Material (Alan R. Eager), 1980 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Guiness Hurling Championship, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - History Ireland Magazines, 2003-2005 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Ireland, 1986-1994 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Ireland in WWII, 1961-1978 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Irish in 18th C Mexico, 1956, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Irish in 19th C Mexico - Juan O'Donoju, 1970-2004 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - The Irish Catholic Experience - A Historical Survey (Patrick J. Corish), 1985 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - The Irish at Home and Abroad (A Journal of Irish Genealogy and Heritage), 1994-1998 (Box 31, Folder 5-7)
  - Irish Language - Ireland, 1993, 1998, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Irish - Mexico General, 1992-2001 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Irish Travelers: U.S., 1995-1997 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Irish Trivia Quiz, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Irish World Wide: O'Sullivan, Patrick I, 1966-1997 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Irish World Wide: O'Sullivan, Patrick I, 1966-1997 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - India, 1996-1999 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Irish v. Irish: Military Encounters, 1959-2001 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Japan and Asia, 1992-1997 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Lamport "Zorro" - Mexico, 2000-2004 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Methodism: Palatines, 1866, 1986, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Mexico: Inquisition, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Mexico: Jaime Fogarty Empresarios, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Monaghan: General, 1971, 1980, 1990-1999 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - A New History of Ireland: Eighteenth-Century Ireland 1691-1800 (T.W. Moody & W.E. Vaughan), 1986 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Papal Army: St. Patrick's Battalion, 1929-1986 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Recollections of Some Sixty Years (Sean S. Reid, O., Carm.), undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - San Patricio Battalion: Mexican Army, Mexican-American War, 1957-2001 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - St. Patrick's Battalion (The Mexican-American War), 1993-2004 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Scotch-Irish 18th C, 1973-2001 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - A Seagrey House: A History of Renvyle House (J.A. Lidwill), undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - South Africa and Boer War, 1964-1995 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Spain I, 1915-2001 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Spain II, 1915-2001 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Wild Geese I, 1907-2001 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Wild Geese II, 1907-2001 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Wild Geese: Bibliography, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Wild Geese: Maritime, 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - World War I: I, 1968-2001 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - World War I: II, 1968-2001 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - World War II, 1964-2001 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Series X: United Irishmen, 1787-2000; 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 11 folders in a second record carton.
  This series contains research materials about the Irish Diaspora as related to the United Irishmen. The contents of this series include photocopies of articles and sometimes books, as well as bibliographic information used by McGinn for his research.
  - United Irishmen (U.I.) I, 1811-1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - United Irishmen (U.I.) II, 1811-1998 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - United Irishmen in North America: General I, 1811-1911, 1938-1999 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - United Irishmen in North America: General I, 1811-1911, 1938-1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Burk, John Daly, 1808-1964 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Charlottesville: Donleavy, Kevin - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Duane, William, 1905, 1960-2000 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Dury, Michal: Articles by, 1987, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Emmet Family, 1915-1999 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Fitzgerald, John: Alexandria, Potomac Co./Convict Transportation I, 1787-1996 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Fitzgerald, John: Alexandria, Potomac Co./Convict Transportation I, 1787-1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Fitzgerald, John, Col.: Potomac Canal Company, 1919-1996 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Humbert, General: Lafitte Louisiana, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Illustrations, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - MacNeven, William I., 1970, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Madden, R.R.: Historian of the United Irishmen, 1971, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - McGinn Papers, 1995-1997 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Morfi, Juan Agustin, New Mexico, TX, 1965, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Samson, William, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - St. Augustine, FL, 1909-1997 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - St. Augustine, FL: 16th and 17th Century - Arthur, Marron, Franciscans, 1909-1998 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - St. Augustine, FL: Church 18th and 19th Century, 1927-1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - St. Augustine, FL: Irish Governors - White, Kindelan, Coppinger, 1975-2000, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - St. Augustine, FL: Forts, Maps, 1926-1977 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Texas Irish Empresarios and Their Colonies" by Oberste, William H., 1953 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Tone Family, 1974-1998 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - United Irishmen in United States, text, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - War of 1812, 1812-1814, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Warden, David Baile, 1916, 1954, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Washington, George: Irish Servants, Cavan Boa, 1898-1999 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - West Indies I, 1894-1999 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - West Indies II, 1894-1999 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Series XI: Korean War Veterans, 1951-2004; 1.95 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 18 folders in a second record carton, and 6 folders in a third record carton.
  This series contains materials related to veterans of the Korean War including documentation on granting of posthumous citizenship to several soldiers. This series also contains photographs of individuals soldiers.
  - A-B (includes photographs), 1951-1952, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - C (includes photographs), 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Casualties - Non-battle, 1997-2001 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Casaulty Count, 2000-2002 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Clare, Sister Mary, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Clues, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Clues (Connolly): FCO 9th Infantry Regiment, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Columban Fathers, 1951-1952, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - D-F (includes photographs), 1952, 2001-2004 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Forms: FOIA, American Battle Monuments Commission, Application for Posthumous Citizenship, 2000-2003 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - G, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - General Research: Death Stats, 2000-2003 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - H, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Herlihy File, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Irish-American Partnership: Kelley, General Paul X, 2000-2003 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Irish Civilians, 1951-1954, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Irish Cultural Society: O'Brien Jack, 2000-2003 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Irish Echo articles, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Irish Government (National Archives), 1951-1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Irish in Korea: History of Site, 2001-2004 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - K (includes photographs), 1953, 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - L, 1953, 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Leahy, John (includes photograph), 1995-2003 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - M-O, 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Mass: St. Patrick's New York, NY, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Mayo Memorial Project: Clarke, P.J. and Feeney, Michael, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Mayo Society, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - McCormack, Michael (includes photograph), 2000-2003 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - McEnery, Patrick (includes photograph), 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - McGinn, Brian: Biography (includes photographs), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - McGuire, James Patrick, 2000-2002 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Mills, William John (Missing in Action); includes photograph, 2000-2004 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Murphy, William (includes photograph), 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), United States, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - O'Brien, Thomas Joseph (includes photographs), 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Posthumous Citizenship, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Posthumous Citizenship Ceremony, Oct 30, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Posthumous Citizenship: First Anniversary, Oct 30, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Posthumous Citizenship: General, Iraq War, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Posthumous Citizenship H.R. 2623 Signed Nov 2, 2002, 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Press Clippings, 2000-2003 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Prior, Owen (includes photographs), 2001-2004 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Prisoners of War, Missing in Action, 2000-2003 (Box 17, Folder 26)